Selim Öber

Principal Consultant at Oracle

selim.ober@gmail.com

Summary

I have seven years' experience in software development and delivery. While most of this time has been spent as a techie, I also co-founded a startup. This allowed me to obtain a broader perspective on business side and gave me the chance to develop team management and product development skills. I'm more a generalist than a specialist, always eager to learn new things. I'm looking for an environment that can offer usable and meaningful products to customers while having an impact on our industry and community.

Experience

Principal Consultant at Oracle

Istanbul, Turkey

October 2011 - Present (1 year 11 months)

I'm working as a consultant in Expert Services. While mostly focused in Middleware, I'm part of an ongoing Oracle Identity Management implementation in Avea Telecom. I'm also in a project manager role for OpenWorld project in Yapi Kredi Bank which is a migration project from mainframe systems to Oracle Exadata. YKB is the largest credit card issuing bank in Turkey, second largest in Europe. Because of the sheer size of the project, many parties are involved in Oracle which I'm mainly responsible of coordinating them and reporting to YKB.

Keywords: Weblogic, IDM, SOA, Coherence, ADF, AOP, Project Management

Senior Developer at Veripark

Istanbul, Turkey

November 2010 - October 2011 (1 year)

Veripark is a software house specialized in providing banking and financial solutions. As an on-site developer at Bank Asya, I've been part of two projects:

- * Corporate Internet Banking: Expansion of the current internet banking portal to the bank's corporate customers. It included adding new security layers, developing a customizable rule engine to control banking transactions, adding administrative capabilities while interacting day-to-day with the customer.
- * Call Center: The call center department of the bank (100+ agents) was operating with many different screens and services. We have developed a new portal that provided a uniform layer to agents which increased their performance and shortened their training time.

In both projects, I've worked in all layers, from DB to ORM and to the UI (JSF) with backing beans.

Keywords: JBoss, Hibernate, JSF, Javascript, CSS

Co-Founder & Developer at Mobil Mecra, Snodd

Istanbul, Turkey - Hyderabad, India

August 2007 - September 2010 (3 years 2 months)

I was the IT guy for this internet start-up. Snodd was initiated as a meeting point for people having similar interests with private shopping elements mixed in. We have developed a very mature framework supporting a dynamic single page application which was quite unique at the time. Relearned Javascript from scratch in the process.

Keywords: IntelliJ, Hibernate, EJB 3.0, GWT, DWR, Dojo, CSS, Javascript (scopes, closures, OO concepts, inheritance...), JBoss, Maven, Agile Methodologies

Developer at Gordion Information Services

Istanbul, Turkey

November 2005 - November 2006 (1 year)

I worked as a developer for WebStart, a CMS product aimed for small to medium sized companies. Although my responsibilities were on development of new features and maintenance, I also directly communicated with clients both for support and training.

Keywords: .Net, C#, MSSQL

Intern at Sagexport, Groupe MAN Ferrostaal AG

Paris, France

June 2004 - August 2004 (2 months)

I was responsible of the development and design of a new Documentation Management System to replace the old one. I participated in design and requirement analysis phases. It's been adopted and actively used by the company after delivery.

Keywords: Microsoft Access, FoxPro

Courses

- Functional Programming Principles in Scala Instructor: Martin Odersky, coursera.org (March, 2013)

- Spring Core Training, Istanbul, Turkey

Instructor: Russell Miles

- CCNA Training, ITU, Istanbul (2004) - Coherence Training

Instructor: Philip Aston, Oracle (January, 2013)

- Speed Reading, Istanbul, Turkey

Instructor: Kivanc Korzay (February, 2010)

Education

B. Sc., Computer Engineering, Galatasaray University (1998 - 2006)Lycée Saint Benoit (1990 - 1998)

Languages

English (Proficient), French (Proficient), Turkish (Native)

Additional Information

Pet Project: I'm developing a Twitter like service for corporate customers, mainly to keep me close to development. The stack I've chosen is Neo4J, Spring (MVC, Data, Security), a RESTful API, Backbone.js, Bootstrap. A very early version of the API is deployed on Heroku. The code base is on bitbucket.org

Geekly weekly: I'm assistant organizer of a weekly meetup (http://www.meetup.com/Istanbul-Hackers)

Kodcu.com: Recently, I started to write in Kodcu.com (http://www.kodcu.com/author/selim.ober)

Hobbies: Ski, sailing, photography, traveling



